The mysterious transfer student, Kazakiri Hyouka, is not human.
（上条(かみじょう)）
謎の転入生―
風斬氷華(かざきり ひょうか)は人間じゃなかった
ＡＩＭ拡散力場が
生みだした物理現象だった
She was a physical phenomenon,
born from all AIM dispersion fields.
But... so what?
けど それが何だってんだ
She's... our friend!
あいつは 俺たちの友達だ
（ｼｪﾘｰ）泣くなよ 化け物
（風斬）ハッ…
Don't cry now, monster.
It's rather disgusting for you to be crying anyway!
（ｼｪﾘｰ）
あなたが泣いても
気持ちが悪いだけなんだし
（上条）
待たせちまったみたいだな
Kept you waiting there, eh?
It's okay now.
もう大丈夫だ
～♪
#23 Friend
Kazakiri Hyouka
（上条）
…たく みっともねえな
God, don't be silly.
Quit crying over something stupid like this.
こんなつまんねえことで
いちいち泣いてんじゃねえよ
エリス！
Ellis!
ハハハッ… 喜べ 化け物
この世界も捨てたものじゃないわね
Rejoice, monster.
This world is rather interesting after all...
そういうバカが
１人くらいは いるんだから
...since there's always some idiot like him...
１人じゃねえぞ
I'm not alone.
W-Why...
どうして…
Come on...
（上条）
ばかばかしい
理由なんて要らねえだろうが
Who needs a reason?
俺は
あいつらに ひと言 言っただけだ
I just said one thing to them.
"Please save my friend."
“友達を助けてほしい”って
Let me show you now...
今から お前に見せてやる
お前の住んでる この世界には
まだまだ救いがあるってことを
...that in this world you reside in...
...there's still hope!
そして 教えてやる
And I'll show you...
お前の幻想は これくらいじゃ
簡単に壊れはしないってことを
...that your illusion...
...won't break down because of small things like this!!!
Ellis, trample! All of them!
（ｼｪﾘｰ）
エリス ぶち殺せ！　１人残らず！
Formation B, protection of the civilians is our top priority!
（警備員(アンチスキル)Ａ）
配置Ｂ　民間人の保護を最優先！
（黄泉川(よみかわ)）撃て！
（銃撃音）
Fire!
ミカエル！　ラファエル！
ガブリエル！　ウリエル！
Michael!
Raphael!
Gabriel!
Uriel!
The four head angels that symbolize the four skies!
四界を示す四天の象徴
正しき力を正しい方向へ
Direct the right power in the right direction...
正しく配置し 正しく導け！
...and guide it to the right position!
（風斬）
ああ… そ… そんな…
（上条）
ここまでは予想どおりってとこだな
Just as expected up to this point.
（上条）
悪い予想のほうってのが
気に入らねえが
I don't like the fact that it's as bad as I'd expected...
Kid, are you really going to do this?
少年　ホントにやる気なの？
おじけづいたって言っても
誰も とがめないじゃん
No one will blame you if you chicken out.
You just saw it, right?
あんたも見たろう　俺の右手の能力
The power of my right hand?
やらなきゃなんねえってのが
正しいけどな
It's probably more like "I have to do this".
Wait... Please wait!
待って　ちょっと待ってください
“やる”って あの… 何を？
Do... Do what?
決まってんだろう
あの化け物を止めてくる
Isn't it obvious?
I'm going to go stop that monster!
…たく ムリしやがって
Acting tough, eh?
やっぱ 月詠(つくよみ)先生は
生徒に恵まれてんじゃん
Tsukuyomi-sensei is blessed with good students after all.
Preparation!
（黄泉川）プリパレーション！
（警備員Ａ）カウント５
Count five!
Count three!
カウント３
アッ… ダメです！
これじゃ絶対 助からない！
Don't!
You'll never make it!
そんなのイヤです！　私…
I don't want that to happen!
I-
Don't stop me, Kazakiri.
（上条）止めるなよ 風斬
（風斬）ハッ…
My right hand will blow away all types of supernatural power.
（上条）
俺の右手は
異能の力なら 善悪を問わず―
It'll neutralize all types of power.
あらゆる力を打ち消しちまう
I'm sure you're no exception.
きっと お前のことも例外じゃない
Count one!
カウント１
別に触れ合うことができなくたって
Just because we can't touch each other...
...doesn't mean I'm not your friend anymore...
お前が友達だってことに
変わりないだろう？
I'll be back.
俺は 必ず帰ってくる
You hear me? I will.
いいか？　必ずだ
...be back...
帰って …くる？
おう　またインデックス連れて
３人で どっかに 遊びに行こうぜ
That's right.
We'll get Index again and go have fun somewhere, the three of us.
Count zero!
カウント０
エリス！
Ellis!
（殴る音）
（上条）ウワッ！
撃て！
（銃撃音）
FIRE!!!
さてと…
Now then...
（ｼｪﾘｰ）
はぁ？　なんだ そりゃ？
What are you trying to do?
これじゃ
お前も逃げられないじゃない
You won't be able to get out of this either.
I don't need to.
（上条）逃げる必要なんかねえよ
（ｼｪﾘｰ）うん？
（ｼｪﾘｰ）ンッ…
I said, I don't need to!
You shut up and take a nap!!!
てめえは黙って…
眠ってろ！
（殴る音）
Now I just need to-
あとは こいつを…
２体目を作る気か？
You're going to create a second one?
一度には
２体も もたせらんねえのさ
I can't sustain two of them at once.
けどな そいつも うまく利用すりゃ
こういうこともできるんだよ
But...
...if I make use of that idea, I can do things like this!
銃撃やめるじゃん！
Cease fire!
くそ… 逃げられたのか
Damn it.
She got away?
（上条）
どういうことだ？
What's the meaning of this?
ターゲットが目の前にいるのに
簡単に逃げるなんて
Her target was right in front of her, yet she just ran away like that...
Think.
思い出せ
何か見落としていることは…
Am I missing anything?
English Purist Church?!
イギリス清教？　インデックスと
同じ組織の人間が なんで…
Why is someone from the same organization as Index...
戦争を起こすんだよ
その火種が欲しいの
I want war.
And I want to create the reason.
だから 多くの人間に 私が―
That's why the more people that know I'm from the English Purist Church, the better!!!
イギリス清教の手駒だって
知ってもらわないとね
（ｼｪﾘｰ）
何ていったかしら？
あのガキの名前
What was the name of that kid again?
まあ ぶち殺すのは
あのガキでなくてもいいし
Well, the one I need to kill doesn't have to be her.
Killing you would be the same!
てめえを殺したって
問題ねえってわけだ！
Index?!
インデックスか！
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）暑いね
（美琴）そうね
It's so hot...
Yeah.
…ていうか
あんたのその服は何なのよ？
But what's with your clothes anyway?
Wearing that much when it's hot as hell...
このくそ暑い中 そんな…
It doesn't bother me.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
別に 気にしたことは
今ではスースーと風通しもいいし
Right now, the wind is blowing and it feels good.
うわ！
安全ピンで留めてるだけじゃない
Holy-
You're just holding it together with safety pins?!
なんで こんなパンクな格好に
なっちゃってるのよ？
How did it end up so messed up?
That brings up some old scars,
いろいろと古傷があるので
深く言及しないでほしいかも
so please don't pursue this issue any further...
（美琴）…にしても 遅いわね
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）うん
But they sure are slow.
なんか あの魔術師は
氷華のことを狙っていたみたいだし
It seemed that magician was targeting Hyouka,
術式もロンドン仕込みみたいな
においがしてたし
and her spells had the indications of the London style.
本当に何にもなければいいけど
I really hope nothing happens.
うん？　氷華ってのは
一緒にいた女の子のこと？
Is Hyouka the other girl that was with us?
うん　あっ 今回は 当麻(とうま)が
引っ張ってきたんじゃないんだよ
Yeah.
Ah, Touma wasn't the one who grabbed the girl this time.
I met her first.
私が先に会ったんだから
“今回は”ねえ　ほほう…
"This time"... eh?
ああ 心配かも 心配かも
あんな所に 女の子が―
Maybe worried... Maybe worried...
I am worried that a girl is left behind in a place like that,
置き去りにされているのも
心配だけど
薄暗闇の中で 当麻と女の子を
２人っきりにさせてるのも心配かも
but I'm also worried about leaving Touma with a girl in a dark place like that...
Who cares about this?
（美琴）
どうでもいいけど あいつの
身の安全は心配してないわけ？
Are you not worried about him at all?
うん？　当麻？　心配ないよ
Touma?
I'm not.
Touma will come back no matter what happens.
当麻は何があっても
絶対に帰ってきてくれるんだから
ふ～ん…
Come back? Whatever.
何よ “帰ってきてくれる”って
まさか あいつ この子と…
Wait, is this girl his-
こら スフィンクス！
Hold it, Sphinx!
いいわよ　ここには私が残るから
Sure.
I'll stay around here, so go grab the cat and hurry back.
あんたは さっさと猫 捕まえて
戻ってきなさい
My body's the kind that cats despise,
so there's no point in me chasing her.
私は猫に嫌われやすい体質だから
追ってもムダだしね
Sorry!
ごめんね　そうしてもらえると
ありがたいかも
I may be somewhat thankful for you doing this!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）スフィンクス！
（美琴）フゥ…
Sphinx!
Come on, wait!
Why isn't the seal on the underground mall being lifted?
（上条）
なんで地下街の封鎖が
解かれないんですか？
地下街の管理とウチらとは
管轄が異なるじゃん
Administration of the underground mall is out of our jurisdiction.
封鎖を解くには
もう少し時間がかかるじゃんよ
They're saying it'll take a little longer before the seal is lifted.
ンッ… くそ！
Damn it!
（風斬）あ… あの…
（上条）うん？
U-Umm...
さっきは ありがとうございました
Thank you very much for what you did.
Sure thing.
Are you okay though?
それより お前 体は大丈夫なのか？
あっ はい　多分 平気だと思います
Y-Yes.
I think I'm okay.
That... golem isn't going to attack us anymore, right?
もう あの石像は
襲ってこないんですよね？
That sneaky lady didn't escape.
あの すすけたゴスロリ女は
逃げたんじゃない
She just started to pursue her next target.
次のターゲットを追い始めただけだ
Her objective isn't to kill you or me, Kazakiri.
あいつの目的は
俺や風斬を殺すことじゃなくて
As long as certain conditions were met,
she could've chosen anyone.
特定の条件さえ そろえば
誰でも良かったんだ
Anyone?
（風斬）誰でも？
（上条）そう
Yeah.
And one of those people... is Index...
そのうちのひとりがインデックス
えっ？　そんな…
No!
But couldn't we ask those people to protect her?
でも それなら あの人たちに頼んで
保護してもらえば…
Index isn't a civilian of this city.
インデックスは
この街の住人じゃない
If Anti-Skill finds her, she might be arrested.
警備員(アンチスキル)に見つかれば
逮捕されるかもしれないんだ
We can't ask them to protect her just like that.
（上条）
うかつに
保護を頼むわけにもいかない
I guess... I just have to go from here...
やっぱ 行くなら ここしかねえか
Damn it.
くそ… 隔壁を開けてくれりゃ
簡単に先回りできるってのに
If only they could open the barricades, I could get there ahead of her easily!
なんで
後手に回らなくちゃならないんだ
Why do I have to play the second hand?
How am I going to get down there?
（上条）
どうやって下りるか…
W-Wait!
（風斬）ま… 待って
（上条）うん？
本当に
あなた１人で行くんですか？
Are you really going to go by yourself?
Index is in danger.
インデックスが危ないんだ
大丈夫 …です
It's... okay...
There's a way to save her... even if you don't go...
あなたが行かなくても
助ける方法はあります
うん？　どういうことだ？
What do you mean?
A monster... for a monster... that's all...
化け物の相手は
化け物がすればいいんです
I don't believe I can defeat that golem...
（風斬）
私は あの石像の化け物に
勝てるとは思えないけど
...but at the very least, I can serve as a bait...
少なくとも 囮(おとり)ぐらいにはなれます
While I'm getting beaten,
（風斬）
私が殴られている隙に
あの子には逃げてもらいます
I'll get her to run away.
I'm just a monster...
私は化け物だから
それぐらいしかできないけど
...and that's all I can do...
Why are you still saying things like that?!
お前 まだ そんなこと言ってんのか
お前は化け物なんかじゃねえ
You're not a monster!
Besides, you think I'd be happy if you did that for me?!
大体 俺が そんなことされて
うれしいとでも思ってんのか？
But that's for the better!
（風斬）だけど それでいいんです
（上条）あっ…
（風斬）
私は化け物でいい
I'm happy being a monster...
化け物だから あの石像に
何度 殴られても死にませんでした
Since I'm a monster, no matter how many times that golem punched me, I didn't die.
Because I'm a monster, I'm able to stand up to that golem.
化け物だからこそ 私は
あの石像に立ち向かえるんです
（風斬）
私は 私の力で大切な人を守ります
I will use my power to protect those I cherish.
だから 私は 化け物で幸せでした
That's why I'm fortunate... to be a monster...
Kazaki-
かざき…
Kazakiri!!!
（上条）
風斬ーっ！
See?
ほら　大丈夫
I'm okay.
Kazakiri... Hyouka?
“風斬氷華”
A place where there's no mass or flow of air,
（風斬）
重さも空気の流れもない
created from the AIM dispersion fields generated by all espers...
能力者たちが放つ
ＡＩＭ拡散力場で作られた―
The city of shimmers.
陽炎(かげろう)の町
学園都市と同じ位置に存在する―
An invisible place that exists in the same location as Academy City.
見えない場所
私は怖かった この陽炎の街が
I was scared of this city of shimmers.
私が見ることで
誰かに役割を与えてしまう
I give someone a role by looking at them.
I destroy someone's life by thinking about them.
私が思うことで
誰かの人生を狂わせてしまう
I am the spring force in a clockwork.
私の役割は ゼンマイ
この社会全体という
巨大なカラクリ細工に―
I breathe life into this clockwork of a society,
命を吹き込んでいく
ゼンマイという一部品
just the part of the spring in this gimmick.
外には出られない
I can't go to the outside world.
外の物や人は見えても
Even if people on the outside see me,
I can't touch or talk to them.
私には 触ることも話すことも
できなかった
But that was the first time...
でも あのとき 初めて…
私は 外の世界に出られた
...I came to the outside world...
Umm...
（風斬）
あの…
ボタン 押さなくちゃ
I think you need to press the button.
Today marked the first time I spoke,
今日 初めて おしゃべりをした
the first time I wore a gym uniform,
初めて 体操服を着た
初めて 男の人に裸を見られた
the first time a man saw my body,
the first time I went to a game center,
初めて ゲームセンターに入った
また裸を見られた
the second time a man saw my body...
Today was the first time I had friends.
今日 初めて友達ができた
If she knew that I was this monster,
私が
こんな化け物だって分かったら―
she might not want to be my friend anymore.
あの子 もう
友達でいてくれないかもしれない
But even so... I...
それでも 私は…
I...
私は…
Hold it, Sphinx!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）こら スフィンクス！
（猫の鳴き声）
If you don't behave, I may just have to punish you for real!
あんまり聞き分けないと
ホントにお仕置きしちゃうかも
Look, we're going back to the meeting area.
ほら 待ち合わせ場所に戻るよ
お返事は？
What's your answer?
足元が揺れてる？
The ground... is shaking?
I want to meet.
I want to believe.
I want to touch it.
ウワッ！
ハァ…
I...
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
基本理論はカバラ
Basic principle is Kabbalah.
Main form of use is defense and elimination of enemies.
主要用途は防衛 敵性の排除
抽出年代は16世紀　応用性あり
Era of extraction is the 16th Century.
Applied nature detected.
Mixing of English Purist Church magic style with original style.
オリジナルに
イギリス清教術式を混合
Linguistic system changed from Hebrew to English.
言語系統は
ヘブライから英語へ変更
From the structure of the spell, determined golem is not in automaton mode, but manipulated from distance.
術式の構成から
自動制御ではなく遠隔操作
Then...
それならば…
ＴＴＴＲ
T T T R - Distort to the left.
Shinkai wo samayou kage
Just a shadow that strolls the deep seas,
ＣＦＡ
C F A - Alter to above.
Kyoufu to mayoi to saigishin
Bearing fear, hesitation, and suspicion.
ＰＩＯＢＴＬＬ
P I O B T L L - Step back with left leg.
Sotto kasa wo hirogeta
Quietly opening its umbrella,
Kokoro kakushiteru jellyfish
This jellyfish who hides its heart.
私には魔術は使えない　でも
魔術を混乱させることならできる
I can't use any magic.
But I can create confusion in the magic.
Spell intercept.
スペルインターセプト
If I can barge into the caster's spell with this forced enchanting-
Tesaguri de ou yume
Pursuing a dream blindly,
術者の制御に割り込みをかける
この強制詠唱なら
Yukue sura shiranu mama
Not knowing where you go.
Ten to chi mo miushinai
Losing track of the Heavens and Earth,
ＣＲ ＢＢＦ
ＴＴＮＡＴＷＩＴＯＤ
C R B B F - Alter to the right. Cross both legs.
Hikari no michi sasu hou e
Simply following the path of light.
T T N A T W I T O D - Turn neck and hip opposite directions.
Evading won't be enough!
さばくだけじゃ足りない
自己修復術式を逆算
その周期は およそ３秒ごと
Reverse-engineering self-regeneration formula.
Period is approximately three seconds.
逆手に取るなら…
If I am to put it at a disadvantage...
There!
そこ！
It may be working.
いけるかも
ウワッ！
C R-
ＣＲ…
ウワッ！
ＭＢＦＰＡＤＣＯＧ
M B F P A D C O G - Position legs in parallel and lose balance.
Aisaretai to negai
Wishing to be loved
Aisuru koto osoreta
But scared to love.
マズイかも
This may be bad...
Konna ni mo itooshii noni
Such a darling,
Long distance manipulation has been switched to automaton mode.
遠隔操作から自動制御に
変更されてる　割り込めない
I can't interfere!
Kimi wa shinjitetai
Or so you believe.
Shinjitsu ga aimai ni
If truth were to transform
Kawatteshimau kurai nara
Into complete vagueness,
Nani mo shiru koto nai
I'd rather not know anything
Touma...
当麻…
Hikari mo todokanu hou e
And follow the path to where light does not reach.
～♪
Next Episode
（上条）
思いが すれ違い
また新たな火種が生まれる
When there is a difference in agenda, new seeds of conflict are born.
たとえ どんなことがあったって
俺たちは ずっと…
No matter what happens,
we will always be...
Next time, "Imaginary Number Sector - Five Elements Institution".
次回 「虚数学区･五行機関」
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる
When science and magic cross paths,
this epic will begin!